【The fate that cannot be liberated】
【无法解脱的命运】
[Episode 9]
[第9集]
[To Jiuling]
[To Jiuling]
General He.
何将军。
Lee adult.
李大人。
gentlemen. he.
先生。他。
I speculate about the marriage between Xingxiang Pavilion and General Mansion
我推测星象阁和将军府的联姻
Will be arranged soon.
很快就会安排。
When will we receive the wedding invitation?
我们什么时候会收到结婚请柬？
My second brother and third brother are not married yet,
我的二弟和三弟 还没有结婚，
So Ling won't get married anytime soon.
所以Ling短时间内不会结婚。
What's more, the young master is seriously ill.
更何况，少爷病重了。
How could he have a wedding?
他怎么能办一场婚礼呢？
My Lords, please watch your words.
各位大人，请注意您的言辞。
I'm already preparing for the wedding.
我已经在准备婚礼了。
That's very good. Then we waited for the wedding invitation.
那挺好的。 然后我们就等待结婚请柬。
I'll take my leave first
我先告辞了
We will definitely bring generous gifts to the wedding.
我们一定会 为婚礼带来丰厚的礼物。
Congratulations.
恭喜。
Yong adult,
容大人，
Rong Yu and Ling are definitely going to get married.
容羽和凌肯定要结婚了。
But I have visited your house many times,
但我曾多次拜访过你的宅邸，
You keep refusing to see me.
你一直拒绝见我。
Why are they bringing up their marriage now?
为什么现在才提起他们的婚姻？
General, you are wrong.
将军，你错了。
I said there is no need for you to come.
我说你没必要过来。
What does this have to do with He Jiuling?
这和何九龄有什么关系？
She is part of my family now
她现在是我家庭的一员
No matter if she is dead or alive.
不管她是死是活。
nonsense! This is complete nonsense.
废话！这完全是无稽之谈。
What does Jiang Rong mean?
姜蓉这话是什么意思？
Does he want me to marry Ling to Rong Yu?
他要我把凌嫁给容玉吗
Let her die there?
让她死在那里？
Ling is the apple of my eye.
凌是我的掌上明珠。
I won't let them torture her.
我不会让他们折磨她。
It doesn't matter what Lord Rong wants.
荣爷想要什么并不重要。
What's important? ? ?
重要的是？？？
Father, do you still want to keep this promise?
父亲，你还想遵守这个诺言吗？
And marry Ling to Rong Yu?
并将凌嫁给容玉？
【He is a mansion】
【他是豪宅】
Not in a hurry.
不着急。
No one showed up the last few nights.
最近几个晚上都没有人出现。
Everyone is here today.
今天大家都到齐了。
I got some good news.
我得到了一些好消息。
my left hand
我的左手
It's now possible to hold things.
现在可以握住东西了。
Sister-in-law, let me serve you some soup.
嫂子，我给你盛汤吧。
- Be careful. - Actually,
- 当心。 - 实际上，
I'm very good at making soup.
我很擅长做汤。
I'll tell you everything next time.
下次我会告诉你一切。
Why don't you eat?
你为什么不吃？
Ling, I'm thinking of a way
玲，我正在想办法
Break off your engagement with Rong Yu.
解除你与容羽的婚约。
Why did you mention this suddenly?
为什么突然提起这个？
This problem will have to be solved sooner or later.
迟早得解决这个问题。
When Rong Yu sent the divorce order,
当容羽送来 断婚令时，
I disagree.
我不同意。
It was my fault.
是我的错。
Rong Yu got the divorce order?
容钰拿到了 断婚令？
Why didn't you tell me earlier?
你为什么不早点告诉我？
At that time I was just
那时我只是
Wants you to marry him.
想让你嫁给他。
How could I possibly tell you?
我怎么可能告诉你呢？
So why now?
那么为什么现在呢？
You think Rong Yu is a fool.
你以为容羽是傻子。
You despise him. You look down on him.
你鄙视他。你看不起他。
So you want me to break off the engagement.
所以你要我解除婚约。
Love that!
喜欢那个！
You are upright, frank, and sharp-eyed.
你为人正直、坦率、目光锐利。
How could it be so vulgar this time?
这次怎么可以这么粗俗呢？
You don't like this marriage either, do you?
你也不喜欢这段婚姻，是吗？
Now father and our big brother are on your side.
现在父亲和我们的大哥 站在你这边。
Why are you not happy?
你为什么不高兴？
You really want to spend your life with a man
你真的很想和一个男人共度一生
Who can't do or understand anything?
谁不能做或理解任何事情？
Why don't you want to marry a true hero who can ride thousands of miles?
你为何不想嫁给一个 能骑万里的真英雄
Across rivers and mountains?
跨越河流和山脉？
If I had broken off the engagement when he was still the eldest son of the family,
如果我在他还是家林大少爷的时候解除了婚约，
I'm very candid.
我很坦率。
But now that he's sick, his future is ruined.
但现在他病了，他的前途就毁了。
If I leave now,
如果我现在离开，
I'm afraid
我耽心
We will be humiliated by everyone.
我们会被所有人羞辱。
Ling, what do you think?
凌，你觉得怎么样？
I
我
Cancel the engagement after he recovers.
等他康复后取消婚约。
What if he doesn't recover?
如果他无法康复怎么办？
He will.
他会的。
Although Master is unwilling to help,
虽然师父不愿意帮忙，
I am his disciple.
我是他的弟子。
I'm making a plan. Will you believe me?
我正在制定一个计划。你会相信我吗？
What if you propose to him soon?
如果你很快就向他求婚怎么办？
Then I will marry him.
那我就嫁给他。
Are you crazy?
你是不是疯了？
I've never been more awake than I am now.
我从来没有像现在这样清醒过。
wide awake?
清醒？
I think you've lost your mind.
我想你已经失去理智了。
you do not know. Jiang Rong? ? ?
你不知道。姜蓉？？？
This is enough.
这就够了。
Ling, sit down.
玲，坐下。
sit down.
坐下。
I have to tell you.
我必须告诉你。
I won't discuss this with you.
我不和你讨论这个问题。
I'm just telling you my decision.
我只是告诉你我的决定。
if someone insults us
如果有人侮辱我们
Let them do it.
让他们去做吧。
But no matter what,
但是，无论怎样，
I will never let you marry Rong Yu.
我绝对不会让你嫁给容羽的。
You shouldn't go anywhere for a while.
一段时间内你不应该去任何地方。
Think this through at home.
在家仔细考虑一下。
- Ling. - let her go.
- 凌。 - 让她走。
Jiuling.
Jiuling.
Pay close attention to her these days.
这几天密切关注着她。
Don't let her out.
不让她出去。
Yes.
是的。
Okay, let's eat.
好吧，我们吃饭吧。
after dinner,
晚饭后，
I have something else to tell you.
我还有事要告诉你。
Jiuling, stop. You're not allowed to go anywhere.
九龄，站住。 你不被允许去任何地方。
Let me go.
让我走。
It's been five days.
已经五天了。
Is something wrong, Miss He?
何小姐有事吗？
However, if something happens to her,
不过，如果她出了什么事的话，
Everyone in the capital will know this.
首都的每个人都会知道这一点。
Master, don't wait any longer.
少爷，别再等了。
She hasn't come yet at this time.
她这个时间还没有来。
I don't think she will come today.
我想她今天不会来。
Why don't we practice speaking or reading words?
我们为什么不练习口语 或阅读单词呢？
Or Heshan can perform a sword dance for you.
或者鹤山可以给你表演剑舞。
His sword dance is very good.
他的剑舞很好。
Your Majesty.
陛下。
The situation on the southern border has become critical.
南疆边境局势 变得危急。
Your Majesty,
陛下，
I am willing to move my family out of the capital
我愿意举家迁出 首都
And went to Nanjiang to defend.
并前往南江据守。
I will take root at the border
我将在边境扎根
Defend Jialin from enemies.
为家林抵御敌人。
Jiuling, attached prescription.
九灵，附方。
If you have any questions, please feel free to drop me a line.
如果您有任何疑问， 请随时给我写信。
come over.
过来。
You two move this over there.
你们两个把这个移到那边去。
Yes.
是的。
- Put this in there. - Yes.
- 把这个放在那里。 - 是的。
Be careful about this. Yes.
对此要小心。是的。
what is going on?
到底是怎么回事？
We may have to move.
我们可能要搬家了。
Why are we moving?
我们为什么要搬家？
My father's position changed.
父亲的立场变了。
We are leaving the capital.
我们要离开首都了。
It seems we are
看来我们是
Take everything away.
带走一切。
correct. We are leaving with our father.
正确的。我们要和父亲一起离开。
And your second brother will never return to the capital.
而你二哥 也不会回京城了。
He will meet us there.
他将在那里与我们会面。
Ling.
凌.
Jiuling.
Jiuling.
Father, why are we leaving the capital?
父亲，我们为什么要离开京城？
My oldest brother loved solving crimes at the Department of Justice.
我的大哥喜欢在司法部破案。
As soon as my second brother returned to the capital, he was immediately promoted.
我二哥 一回到京城，立刻就升职了。
He San wanted to enter the palace and serve as King Wu's bodyguard.
禾三欲入宫担任金吾侍卫。
He had been preparing for the spring exam for so long.
为了春试，他准备了 这么久。
Just because of my marriage,
仅仅因为我的婚姻，
Everyone had to give up everything they were doing.
每个人都必须放弃手头的一切。
And leave here forever.
并永远离开这里。
If we want to serve the country
如果我们想报效国家
and make friends,
并结交朋友，
We can do this anywhere.
我们可以在任何地方做到这一点。
Well, I'm not going. I'll stay here.
好吧，我不去。我会留在这儿。
I will wait for Rong Yu to recover.
我会等容羽康复。
No one will stay here.
没有人会留在这里。
The emperor learned that you are practicing martial arts in school.
皇上得知 你在学校习武。
So he awarded you the title of General Zuo.
于是他就授予 你左将军的称号。
You have no choice.
你别无选择。
Why don't you ask for my opinion?
你为什么不征求我的意见？
Because I know your opinion.
因为我知道你的意见。
Do you think you married Rong Yu?
你觉得你嫁给容宇了吗
Will it change his current situation?
会改变他现在的处境吗？
- Father. - Don't you think this is torture for me too?
- 父亲。 - 你不觉得这对我来说也是一种折磨吗？
If you insist,
如果你坚持的话，
It doesn't matter.
没关系。
I would sacrifice everyone in our family.
我会牺牲我们家里的每个人
to Rong Yu.
to Rong Yu.
Chenzhou,
郴州,
tell her
告诉她
What Rong Yu said.
容宇所说的话。
Rong Yu said that if his father insists on guarding the border,
容羽说 ，如果父亲坚持守卫边境，
His contributions would make emperors and ministers fear him.
他的贡献会让皇帝 和大臣们畏惧。
This will not end well for my father.
父亲不会有好下场。
N-not
N-非
It ends well.
结局很好。
DD-Mold
DD-模具
In combat?
在战斗中？
Died for the family forest,
为家林而死，
for the people,
为了人民，
It is the glory of our family.
是我们家族的荣耀。
so,
所以，
Rong Yu's prophecy
容羽的预言
I'm not scared at all.
我一点也不害怕。
Yihua and I are also willing to die for Jialin.
我和宜华也愿意为家琳去死。
Qingxing and Qiu Ting will not live alone.
庆星和秋婷也不会单独生活。
Ling,
凌,
This time it's not all about you.
这次不全是关于你的。
The emperor mentioned many times
皇帝曾多次提到
Borders need to be guarded.
边境需要守卫。
We couldn't say no.
我们无法拒绝。
Follow me and your brothers into battle,
跟随我和你的兄弟 奔赴战场，
In order to protect the people of Jialin,
为了保护嘉林人民，
It can also ensure Rong Yu’s safety.
也能保证容羽的安全
for the rest of his life.
他的余生。
Ling,
凌,
I also want to see you get married and have children.
我也想看到你结婚 生子。
I want to see your happy life.
我想看到你幸福的生活。
but if i stay in the capital
但如果我留在首都
Saw you marrying a fool
看到你嫁给一个傻瓜
And was scolded and tortured by others,
并受到别人的责骂和折磨，
Why do I have to live such a miserable life?
为什么我要过这样痛苦的生活
And give up my strength of character?
并放弃我的性格力量？
even better is
更好的是
I'm going the way we should be going.
我走的是我们应该走的路。
Now that we've reached this point,
既然我们已经到了这一步，
stay or leave,
留下或离开，
up to you.
由你决定。
I don't believe there is heaven
我不相信有天堂
Nor in destiny.
也不在命运中。
I believe that humans have the ability to conquer nature.
我相信人类有能力征服自然。
I, He Jiuling,
I, He Jiuling,
I am willing to die for Jialin .
我愿意为家林献身 而死。
be prepared.
做好准备。
We will set off for Nanjiang
我们将出发前往南江
the day after tomorrow.
后天。
Rong Yu,
Rong Yu,
If we knew the outcome from the beginning
如果我们从一开始就知道结果
Shouldn't I give you hope?
我不应该给你希望吗？
Even though I really want to see you again
尽管我真的很想再次见到你
before we part,
在我们分别之前，
but,
但，
I can not.
我不能。
I shouldn't.
我不应该。
Please forget about me for a moment.
请暂时忘记我。
There are many rare and exotic grasses in Nanjiang .
南江 有许多珍奇奇草。
I will prepare an antidote
我会配制解药
as soon as possible.
尽快地。
【Rong's Mansion】
【荣氏府邸】
The master is here.
主人来了。
Master, take a look.
少爷你看一下。
This is the note you wrote earlier. Take it.
这是你之前写的笔记。拿去。
Does he come to study every day?
他每天都来读书吗？
Yes, he just doesn’t know him well yet.
是的，他只是还不太认识。
The wind is a bit strong.
风有点大。
The young master’s fault is bad.
少爷的不好。
And there's no stove here.
而且这里没有炉子。
Don't come here again.
别再来这里了。
You can get him whatever he wants to read .
他想读什么， 你都可以给他拿。
Yes.
是的。
This is the owner's thing.
这是主人的东西。
- be careful. - Yes Yes.
- 小心一点。 - 是的是的。
Be careful.
当心。
Ling, how is the packaging?
玲，包装怎么样了？
We'll leave early tomorrow morning.
我们明天一早就出发。
Have you packed everything?
你把所有东西都收拾好了吗？
Jiuling, Atan said she will come to see you off tomorrow morning.
九灵，阿檀说明 天早上她会来送你。
I'm going out to say goodbye to a few close friends later.
稍后我要出去告别 几个亲密的朋友。
perhaps,
或许，
We won't be back.
我们不会再回来了。
Maybe,
也许，
We will die on the Nanjiang battlefield.
我们将死在南江战场。
Will never come back.
永远不会回来。
Never see him again.
再也见不到他了。
???A bouquet of flowers? ? ?
??? 一束花 ？？？
??? bloom for you? ? ?
??? 为你绽放？？？
??? wonderful love? ? ?
??? 美好的爱情？？？
??? Make me cry and sad? ? ?
??? 让我哭泣和悲伤？？？
??? A touch of lovesickness makes me sad? ? ?
??? 淡淡的相思让我悲伤？？？
???I can only promise you the next life? ? ?
??? 我只能向你许诺下辈子？？？
Master.
少爷。
??? I am crazy for you. Will I stay and find you? ? ?
??? 我为你疯狂。 我会留下来找你？？？
???Give me love in the next life? ? ?
??? 赐予我下辈子的爱？？？
??? Lend me the wish of this life? ? ?
??? 借我此生的心愿？？？
??? I want to become a butterfly and be obsessed with flowers like you? ? ?
??? 我想变成一只蝴蝶， 迷恋你这样的花？？？
???The land is still the same? ? ?
??? 土地还是一样？？？
??? Can withstand spring rain and autumn rain? ? ?
??? 经得起春雨秋雨？？？
Rong Yu.
Rong Yu.
Master, where are you going?
少爷，你要去哪里？
Slow down, Master. slow down.
慢点吧，少爷。减速。
???A bouquet of flowers? ? ?
??? 一束花？？？
??? bloom for you? ? ?
??? 为你绽放？？？
??? wonderful love? ? ?
??? 美好的爱情？？？
??? Make me cry and sad? ? ?
??? 让我哭泣和悲伤？？？
??? A touch of lovesickness makes me sad? ? ?
??? 淡淡的相思让我悲伤？？？
???I can only promise you the next life? ? ?
??? 我只能向你许诺下辈子？？？
how dare you! Who dares to break into Rong Mansion?
你怎么敢！ 谁敢闯入荣府？
???Give me love in the next life? ? ?
??? 赐予我下辈子的爱？？？
??? Lend me the wish of this life? ? ?
??? 借我此生的心愿？？？
??? I want to become a butterfly and be obsessed with flowers like you? ? ?
??? 我想变成一只蝴蝶， 迷恋你这样的花？？？
???The land is still the same? ? ?
??? 土地还是一样？？？
??? Can withstand spring rain and autumn rain? ? ?
??? 经得起春雨秋雨？？？
??? I am destined to meet you and wait for your return? ? ?
??? 命中注定我会遇见你， 等你归来？？？
???Give me love in the next life? ? ?
??? 赐予我下辈子的爱？？？
??? Lend me the wish of this life? ? ?
??? 借我此生的心愿？？？
??? I want to become a butterfly and be obsessed with flowers like you? ? ?
??? 我想变成一只蝴蝶， 迷恋你这样的花？？？
???The land is still the same? ? ?
??? 土地还是一样？？？
??? Can withstand spring rain and autumn rain? ? ?
??? 经得起春雨秋雨？？？
??? I am destined to meet you and wait for your return? ? ?
??? 命中注定我会遇见你， 等你归来？？？
Since you are leaving tomorrow, why do you come here?
既然你明天就要走，为什么还要来这里？
what are you waiting for?
你在等什么？
Pulled the young master back.
把少爷拉了回来。
Yes Yes.
是的是的。
Be gentle. Don't hurt him.
要温柔。别伤害他。
Master, Master, please come down.
少爷，少爷，请下来。
Be careful, Master.
小心一点，少爷。
Master.
少爷。
Master, Master.
少爷，少爷。
Be careful, Master. Be careful.
小心一点，少爷。当心。
Be careful, Master.
小心一点，少爷。
Rong Yu.
Rong Yu.
come over.
过来。
How lucky I am in this life.
我这一生是多么幸运啊。
Starting tonight,
从今晚开始，
I may never see you again.
我可能再也见不到你了。
Rong Yu.
Rong Yu.
even if i am
即使我是
far away from you
离你很远
I will pray for you.
我会为你祈祷。
I am leaving.
我走了。
Don't miss me.
不要错过我。
I have no future.
我没有未来。
forget me.
忘了我。
Rong Yu.
Rong Yu.
[Jialin]
[Jialin]
What Lord?
何主。
I wish you a safe journey.
祝您旅途平安。
careful.
小心。
Miss He.
何小姐。
painting.
绘画。
This is Master Rong’s portrait for you.
这是容大师的肖像给您。
Don't be so gloomy.
别这么阴郁。
Go and stop the young master.
快去拦住少爷。
Master, Master, Master, Master.
少爷，少爷， 少爷，少爷。
——He Jiuling. - You can't go out.
——何九龄。 - 你不能出去。
I want to find He Jiuling.
我要找到贺九菱。
【Rongfu】 You can't go out.
【荣府】 你不能出去。
Master.
少爷。
[Nanjiang]
[Nanjiang]
The second sister-in-law's throwing skills have improved again.
二嫂的摔技术 又进步了。
This time, even I couldn't see the flaw.
这一次，连我都看不出破绽了。
You're asking for a beating.
你这是在要求挨打。
Stop fooling around.
停止瞎闹。
Jiuling's swordsmanship is getting better and better.
九灵的剑法 越来越好了。
After dinner, I want to have a fight with you.
吃完晚饭，我想和你打一架。
Give me a break.
让我休息一下。
You are the weakest one in the family.
你是家里最弱的一个。
If you were my sparring partner, I would feel like this is a waste of my time.
如果你是我的陪练， 我会觉得这是浪费我的时间。
He Jiuling, don't be so proud.
贺九菱，别这么得意。
One day, I will definitely be able to defeat you.
总有一天，我一定能打败你。
Jiuling, lie down.
Jiuling, lie down.
look. I knocked down the best
看。我击倒了 最杰出的人
In our home.
在我们家。
He Qiuting, you are really looking for death.
何秋婷，你真是找死啊。
It's time to go home and have dinner.
该回家吃晚饭了。
let's go.
我们走吧。
I really hate these twins.
我真的很讨厌这对双胞胎。
Do you want to quarrel or eat?
你想吵架还是想吃饭？
eat you. May I?
吃了你。可以吗？
What did you say? I didn't hear it.
你说什么？我没听到。
running. running. running.
跑步。跑步。跑步。
The second sister-in-law is going to beat us.
二嫂要打我们了。
Let's eat.
我们吃饭吧。
I love you.
我爱你。
Be good.
乖一点。
The second sister-in- law drinks a lot.
二嫂 酒量很大。
Drink more.
多喝点。
Why do you say these things to him every day?
你为什么每天对他说这些话？
you must. He can understand.
你必须。他能理解。
You just need to say it once a day.
你只需要每天说一遍。
Mom loves you.
妈妈爱你。
Then he will be beautiful
这样他就会很漂亮
It’s a pleasure to be your child.
很高兴成为您的孩子。
Brother, you have to say this too.
大哥，这话你也得说啊。
Say it. Say it now. I want to hear it.
说吧。现在就说吧。我想听听。
What should I say?
我应该说什么？
Say, daddy loves you.
说，爸爸爱你。
No, I can not.
不，我不能。
Come on, brother. Say it.
快点啊大哥。说吧。
Say it.
说吧。
explain? ? ? All right. I'll say it.
说？？？好吧。我会说的。
I? ? ?
我？？？
- eat. eat. - Eat.
- 吃。吃。 - 吃吧。
Stop embarrassing him.
别再让他难堪了。
Please have a meal
请吃饭吧
Now, our sister-in-law is the most important thing.
现在，我们的大嫂 才是最重要的。
here,
这里，
There is a chicken drumstick.
有一个鸡腿。
no no.
不，不。
They cook just for me every day.
他们每天专门为我做饭。
I can't eat that much.
我吃不了那么多。
Just eat this?
就吃这个吧？
This is for you, Ling.
这是给你的，凌。
Thanks.
谢谢。
This is for you, Father.
这是给你的，父亲。
OK
好的。
You've just recovered from a cold.
你刚刚从感冒中恢复过来。
You still have to take care of yourself.
你还是要保重身体。
All right.
好吧。
Ling, give you another one.
凌，再给你一份。
I'm done.
我受够了。
Thank you, Jiuling. I love you.
谢谢你，九龄。我爱你。
Nowadays, it is really rare for the whole family to be together.
如今，一家人都齐聚一堂，真是难得。
Let's drink together.
我们一起干杯吧。
cheers.
干杯。
In this year’s martial arts competition in Nanjiang,
今年南江的武术比赛中，
First prize is a co-leadership position.
一等奖是联合领导职位。
There are also rewards for other levels,
其他等级也有奖励，
It's just some medicinal materials like nine-segmented beetles.
只是一些九节虫甲虫之类的药材而已。
It is nothing special.
没什么特别的。
Qiuting,
Qiuting,
Don't just eat.
不要只是吃。
Do you want to register?
您想注册吗？
Although I am good at martial arts,
虽然我武功不错，
There is always someone else better.
总有其他人更好。
I don’t think I’ll sign up.
我想我不会注册。
If you think so, you can still get better.
如果你这么想，你仍然可以变得更好。
Chenzhou, register him.
郴州，给他登记一下。
- Father. I? ? ? - Horseback archery, sticks, spears, knives,
- 父亲。我？？？ - 骑马射箭、棍棒、矛、刀、
Sword, array, hook, halberd, dart? Which one do you choose?
剑、阵、钩、戟、镖？ 你选择哪一个？
which one?
哪一个？
for me,
为我，
There is no difference. I? ? ?
没有什么区别。我？？？
OK Since there is no difference,
好的。既然没有区别，
I would just register everything for him.
我只会为他登记一切。
What? What?
什么？什么？
Did you two lie to me on purpose?
你们两个是故意骗我的吧？
Jiuling won first place last year.
去年九灵获得了第一名。
Won't she be allowed to participate this year?
今年不让她参加吗？
Why are you messing with me?
你为什么要惹我？
???Under the sunset at dusk? ? ?
??? 黄昏夕阳下？？？
???I traveled thousands of miles to a distant place? ? ?
??? 我千里迢迢去远方？？？
???Playing the piano under the moonlight? ? ?
??? 月下弹琴？？？
???These drinks won’t make me forget? ? ?
??? 这些饮料不会让我忘记？？？
???The desire I wrote for you? ? ?
??? 我写下的对你的渴望？？？
??? Our destiny is written on paper? ? ?
??? 我们的命运是写在纸上的？？？
??? Like the strongest wine? ? ?
??? 就像最烈的酒一样？？？
??? There is no way to escape fate? ? ?
??? 命运无路可逃？？？
???Looking back, I saw you waiting? ? ?
??? 回头一看，我看到你在等待？？？
???Our life is full of joy and sorrow? ? ?
??? 我们的生活充满欢乐和悲伤？？？
??? Desire to crystallize into a bright galaxy???
??? 渴望结晶 成明亮的银河???
???You quietly turned around and closed the marriage certificate? ? ?
??? 你悄悄转身 合上了婚书？？？
???Ask how many stars are there in the sky? ? ?
??? 问天上有多少颗星星？？？
???The desire I wrote for you? ? ?
??? 我写下的对你的渴望？？？
??? Our destiny is written on paper? ? ?
??? 我们的命运是写在纸上的？？？
??? Like the strongest wine? ? ?
??? 就像最烈的酒一样？？？
??? There is no way to escape fate? ? ?
??? 命运无路可逃？？？
???Looking back, I saw you waiting? ? ?
??? 回头一看，我看到你在等待？？？
???Our life is full of joy and sorrow? ? ?
??? 我们的生活充满欢乐和悲伤？？？
??? Desire to crystallize into a bright galaxy???
??? 渴望结晶 成明亮的银河???
???I gently caress the guzheng, waiting for passers-by like you???
??? 我轻轻抚着古筝， 等待着你这样的路人???
???So you are my indissoluble bond? ? ?
??? 原来你就是我的不解之缘？？？